NAINA VERMA

Bengaluru(karnataka)

09041477157/9739331020 • naina.verma7@gmail.com https://nainav.github.io/

ORIFCTIVES

To gain knowledge and build a career in a challenging and professional environment that gives good opportunities to learn and apply the latest technologies leading to professional growth, and seeking a position to utilize my skills and abilities in the industry while being resourceful, innovative and flexible.

SOFTWARE QUALITY ASSURANCE ENGINEER

4+ year of experience in Automation and manual testing for Software Quality Assurance from September 2013 – to present at Dell EMC(Bangalore). Plus, with the experience at Zscaler and Red Hat. Knowledgeable in Open-Source Automation Tools (Selenium, Agile) Familiar with Object-Oriented Programming in Perl, Python and Javascript. Four month Industrial Training in Quality Assurance at InfoTech Enterprises Pvt. ltd. Noida, 2013.

KEY SKILLS

Analysis

SQA Tools & Best
Practices
Test Cases, Plans &
Scripts
Defect & Bug Discovery
Technical Specification

Tracking, Logging & Reporting
Program Logic & Optimization
Software Architecture
Technologies
Issue Identification & Documentation

Full stack development using Angular 2+, MongoDB(Python flask),Express server,Node JS for server side scripting.

HighCharts analytics with Angular2

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating System Linux(Ubuntu) Windows

Language Core Java, J2EE, Perl scripting, Python scripting

Testing FrameworkTestNg, PywinautoDatabaseMySql , PostgreSQL.ServerApache Tomcat

Web Technologies HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Jquery, Json, Ajax, XML, Highcharts

Application Stack JDK1.6, JDK1.7, Eclipse IDE, Pyscripter

Log frameworkLog4j and LogbackRepositorySVN, GIT, docker

Build tool Maven

Other tools Ovf tool, Vim-cmd

Networking tools Wireshark,dummynet,Fiddler,OpenSSL.

Professional Experience

Dell Emc — Bangalore Quality Engineer,

July /2017 to present Working on front end and business logic development and Project management staff to capture requirements for the functional elements of the application and also responsible for liaising with clients and ensuring that all work carried out complies with standards And guidelines.

Contributions:

- Web-Development (GUI): Development in Angular 4 for the automation project of performance automation team.
- Involvement in Git process: Reviewing and guiding team related to Git process for the automation project.
- Fixing issues and writing Backend REST API using python(flask) with mongodb.

Redhat - Bangalore Quality Engineer,

April -2016 to June - 2017

Perform system, acceptance, regression, load and functional performance testing on application using both automated and manual testing methods. Leverage knowledge of object oriented programming to help validate, verify, communicate and resolve software issues.

Contributions:

- Excelled in finding, documenting and reporting bugs, errors, interoperability flaws and other issues within open source software applications developed by Redhat
- **Demonstrated methodical, detail-oriented and thorough approach** to all assignments while adhering to compressed timelines. Complete all assignments on or ahead of schedule.

Zscaler — Chandigarh Junior QA Tester, Sep/2013 to Present

Perform system, unit, acceptance, regression, load and functional performance testing on dozens of applications using both automated and manual testing methods. Leverage knowledge of object-oriented programming to help validate, verify, communicate and resolve software issues.

Contributions:

- Excelled in finding, documenting and reporting bugs, errors, interoperability flaws and other issues within proprietary software applications developed for Zscaler Company's global user base.
- **Demonstrated methodical, detail-oriented and thorough approach** to all assignments while adhering to compressed timelines. Complete all assignments on or ahead of schedule.
- Consistently recognized for excellent problem-solving and analytical skills by programmers, project managers and supervisors.

EDUCATION

- Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology from Bhai Gurdas Institute of Engineering and Technology, Sangrur under Punjab Technical University with an aggregate 83% in 2013.
- Completed class 12th from PSEB 67% in 2009.
- Completed class 10th from PSEB 81% in 2007.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Rising Star Winner for the Java Automation Framework in Zscaler Chandigarh 2014.
- Topper with 83% in IT Department at Bhai Gurdas Institute of Engg and Tech 2013.
- Worked as Coordinator of Non-Technical event in college Tech-Fest 'Armageddon 7.0' 2013.

Professional Experience

Redhat — Bangalore Quality Engineer, April /2016 to Present

Perform system, acceptance, regression, load and functional performance testing on application using both automated and manual testing methods. Leverage knowledge of object-oriented programming to help validate, verify, communicate and resolve software issues.

Contributions:

- Excelled in finding, documenting and reporting bugs, errors, interoperability flaws and other issues within open source software applications developed by Redhat.
- **Demonstrated methodical, detail-oriented and thorough approach** to all assignments while adhering to compressed timelines. Complete all assignments on or ahead of schedule.

Zscaler Pvt. ltd. — Chandigarh

Junior Software Engineer, September /2013 to April 2016 (2 years 8 months)

Performed tests to assure the quality of proprietary software application developed by Zscaler Pvt. Ltd and file bugs and generate issue tracker reports.

EDUCATION

- Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology from Bhai Gurdas Institute of Engineering and Technology, Sangrur under Punjab Technical University with an aggregate 83% in 2013.
- Completed class 12th from PSEB 67% in 2009.
- Completed class 10th from PSEB 81% in 2007.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating System Linux, Windows

LanguagePython scripting, Perl scriptingTesting FrameworkProtractor, TestNg, Pywinauto

Database PostgreSQL.

Containers technology Docker **Configuration** Ansible

management tools

Web Technologies Javascript, Json

Application Stack VS code ,Eclipse IDE,Pyscripter

SCM GIT

Build tool Mayen

Development stack Mongodb, Angular 2+, Node JS

CURRENT PROJECT

Project Title Continuous Performance Automation

Project Type User Interface to display automation statistics

Operating System Cross platform

Areas of Development Rest(API),UI(Analytics reporting)

DataBase MongoDB

Tools UsedVisual Studio, GIT , Angular 4 **Role**Quality Engineer Automation

Team Size 8-9

Description:

This project is to give management overall picture about performance testing efforts. UI will display statistics of test executions (automation) results, Baseline and benchmarking comparison.

Responsibilities:

Working on front end and business logic development and Project management

staff to capture requirements for the functional elements of the application and also responsible for

liaising with clients and ensuring that all work carried out complies with standards And quidelines.

Key Roles to automate:

- Baseline and Benchmarking analytics for the product by using Highcharts and graph
- Aggregated reports of the test executions.
- Writing Generic API's: Creating API's to be consumed by other projects as well to reuse the
- efforts.

REDHAT PROJECT

Project TitleContainer Development Kit (CDK)Project TypeDevelopment kit for developers

Operating System Windows, Linux

Areas of Testing Containers Developement kit

Framework used Avocado framework

Tools Used GIT, Docker , Kubernetes , openshift , Vagrant

Role Quality Engineer

Team Size 4

Description:

CDK is developer kit for developing application ,to provide developers from having to assemble a container development environment from scratch, Container Development Kit delivers the latest container tools in a Red Hat Enterprise Linux virtual machine that you can use on your macOS, Microsoft Windows, or Red Hat Enterprise Linux system.

Responsibilities:

Gather test requirement and perform manual tests. Automate tests using python framework. Write Anisble scripts to run the tests on Multiple OS Mac , Windows , Linux . Report issues in JIRA with troubleshooting results.

REDHAT PROJECT

Project Title <u>Fabric8-planner</u>

Project Type Application Lifecycle Management System

Operating SystemWindows, LinuxAreas of TestingRest(API),UI

Framework used Angular 2, Protractor, Perf Cake , frisby

DatabasePostgresqlTools UsedGIT, Vs codeRoleQuality Engineer

Team Size 2

Description:

Fabric8 planner is component of application lifecycle management system, its issue tracker system. The overall aim project is to give user ability to plan, code, build, test and deploy the projects.

Responsibilities:

ZSCALER PROJECT

Project Title ZSHIFT

Project Type Cloud Security Solution

Operating System Windows, Linux

Areas of Testing Rest(API), UI, DNS Proxy, SSL, Analytics reporting

Database Postgresql

Tools Used Eclipse Indigo, GIT **Role** Software Engineer

Team Size 2

Description: Intelligent routing automatically applies adaptive security policy to dynamic Internet threats; Cloud-based service extends enterprise-class security architecture to broader market.

Responsibilities: Working on front end and business logic development and Project management staff to capture requirements for the functional elements of the application and also responsible for liaising with clients and ensuring that all work carried out complies with standards And guidelines. Key Roles to automate:

- **Ubiquitous Security** Transparently enforce security and corporate policies from a single pane of glass without impacting end user experience.
- Comprehensive Visibility An intuitive dashboard provides instant insight into security posture,

malicious activity and internet browsing trends, consolidating and correlating this information across the entire organization in real-time.

• **Granular Policy Management** – Select one of four risk tolerance settings to instantly enforce common policies with the click of a button or select specific Internet browsing categories to create a custom policy.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Good performer award in Dell EMC 2018.
- Trust and Collaboration award from the team .
- Rising Star Winner for the Java Automation Framework in Zscaler Chandigarh 2014.
- Topper with 83% in IT Department at Bhai Gurdas Institute of Engg and Tech 2013.
- Worked as Coordinator of Non-Technical event in college Tech-Fest 'Armageddon 7.0' 2013.